Helen G. Sullivan papers M2149
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Helen G. Sullivan papers
1945-1952
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Sullivan, Helen G.
M2149
0.63 Linear Feet One legal mb and one half box
Biographical / Historical
Helen Gray Sullivan was born in 1923 and grew up in Winston-Salem, North Carolina. She graduated from the Woman's College of the University of North Carolina in 1944, and then went into service with the Office of the Director of Political Affairs, a division of the Office of Military Government, United States (OMGUS) and was stationed in Berlin, Germany, where she remained for several years working for the military government of occupied Germany. She returned to the United States in 1948, and worked for the United States Foreign Service in Washington, D.C. Helen was the youngest daughter of Ralph Alexander Sullivan (1888-1974) and Elizabeth Sullivan (1898-1973). She had an older sister, Marjorie, and a younger brother, Ralph.
Content Description
Contains 130 letters, both manuscript and typescript, (99 retained mailing envelopes), plus 137 photographs and 45 pieces of paper ephemera, all dated 1945 to 1952. The correspondence is between Helen G. Sullivan and her family, mostly written while Helen was stationed at Berlin in post war occupied Germany working for the Office of the Director of Political Affairs. The majority of the letters are from Helen to her family members, but the collection also includes letters to Helen from her mother (Elizabeth Sullivan), Ralph Paxman (a postal officer), and others.
The archive includes 137 black and white photographs taken by Helen Sullivan, as well as postcards from Germany.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was purchased for Stanford University, Special Collections in August 2016.
Related Materials
The State Archives of North Carolina Military Collection holds the Helen G. Sullivan Letters (CLDW 11).
Germany -- History -- 1945-1955; Sullivan, Helen G.; Germany (Territory under Allied occupation, 1945-1955: U.S. Zone). Office of Military Government
- Letters - Helen Sullivan to her parents and siblings, January - June 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters - Helen Sullivan to her parents and siblings, July - December 1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letters - Helen Sullivan to her parents and siblings, January - June, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letters - Helen Sullivan to her parents and siblings, July - December 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letters - Helen Sullivan to her parents and siblings, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letters - Helen Sullivan to her parents and siblings, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters - Helen Sullivan to her parents and siblings, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letters - Mrs. Elizabeth Sullivan to her daughter, Helen Sullivan, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letters - Mrs. Elizabeth Sullivan to her daughter, Helen Sullivan, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Letters to Mrs. Elizabeth Sullivan from Ralph Paxman, postal officer, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Letters to Helen Sullivan, various, 1945 -1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Letters to Helen Sullivan, various, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Ephemera, including programs, receipts, Christmas greetings, birthday telegrams, postcards from Helen Sullivan to family (Half-box 2, Folder 1)
- Photographs from loose pages of photograph albums - black and white (Half-box 2, Folder 2)
- Photographs of people, including class photos and portraits - black and white (Half-box 2, Folder 3)
- Photographs of travel - black and white (Half-box 2, Folder 4)
- Photographs of office - black and white (Half-box 2, Folder 5)